The next thing I'm going to talk about is fire safety.
As you will see later on, this grinder does throw quite a bunch of sparks.
That's why I have this bucket here.
It allows the sparks, most of the sparks to go into the water and settle to the bottom.
Also, if for some reason a fire does start out and you don't have access to your fire extinguisher right close by (though I do suggest that you have a fire extinguisher close by at all times).
A good fire extinguisher to have is one that says ABC, so that it's good for trash and paper and wood as well as liquids and electrical fires.
So it covers all the generals that you need.
But also, you have this bucket of water so that if something happens, you have a bunch of water here that you can use.
This water is also used to cool down the knives so that you don't burn your hands.
The other thing that you want to make sure of is that you are not grinding next to flammable liquids.
The sparks do end up on the floor, sometimes they shoot out the back.
You want to make sure there's no oily rags or paper that's going to catch on fire, because the sparks that come off of here are pretty hot and if there's something to catch on fire, it will catch on fire.
And another thing you want to remember is this: if you are doing this in an enclosed area like a garage or a shop, make sure that it's properly ventilated, and that you don't have cans of gasoline around where the fumes can accumulate on the floor, because the sparks will end up down there.
And it will start a massive fire, and create a lot of destruction.